<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title/><link>https://pouroverdata.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 17:44:48 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pouroverdata.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Roasting Coffee</title><link>https://pouroverdata.github.io/blog/roasting-coffee/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 17:44:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://pouroverdata.github.io/blog/roasting-coffee/</guid><description>Coffee roasting is the process of heating green coffee beans in order to convert them into the dark, flavorful, and aromatic roasted coffee beans that we use to make coffee. There are various types of coffee roasters, including drum roasters, air roasters, and fluid bed roasters.
Before the invention of coffee roasters, early adopters of coffee were roasting their coffee using various methods. One of the most common methods was using a skillet or pan on an open flame.</description></item><item><title>Coffee Genome</title><link>https://pouroverdata.github.io/blog/coffee-genome/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 12:58:14 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://pouroverdata.github.io/blog/coffee-genome/</guid><description>There have been a number of sequencing studies that have been conducted on coffee species, primarily on Coffea canephora (robusta) and Coffea arabica (arabica), which are the two most widely cultivated species of coffee. In 2010, the first draft genome of Coffea canephora was published by an international consortium led by the French Agricultural Research Centre for International Development (CIRAD). The genome assembly consisted of 36,336 scaffolds and its size was estimated at around 940 Mb.</description></item><item><title>Coffee to Water Ratio</title><link>https://pouroverdata.github.io/blog/coffee-to-water-ratio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 09:24:19 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://pouroverdata.github.io/blog/coffee-to-water-ratio/</guid><description>History of Coffee Coffee has been around for centuries and it all began in Ethiopia with a goat herder named Kaldi. He noticed his goats getting hyper after eating some red berries and decided to try it himself. He found that it gave him energy too. The local monks found out about it and started using it to stay awake during long religious ceremonies.
As word spread, coffee made its way to the Arab world and became a hit in places like Mecca and Medina.</description></item><item><title>How to Brew Coffee</title><link>https://pouroverdata.github.io/blog/how-to-brew-coffee/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 21:16:36 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://pouroverdata.github.io/blog/how-to-brew-coffee/</guid><description>There are many ways to brew coffee, some common methods include drip brewing, French press, and pour over. The strength of the brew is determined by the ratio of coffee grounds to water. A general guideline is to use 1 to 2 tablespoons of ground coffee for every 6 ounces of water. However, this can be adjusted to personal taste. The roast level (light, medium, dark) can also affect the strength of the brew.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to Pour Over data blog</title><link>https://pouroverdata.github.io/blog/my-first-blog/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 18:04:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://pouroverdata.github.io/blog/my-first-blog/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Where coffee meets data!&amp;rdquo;
Welcome to Pour Over Data, a website dedicated to exploring the intersection of data science, bioinformatics, and machine learning using coffee-related datasets and beyond. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a coffee aficionado or simply interested in the latest developments in data science, you&amp;rsquo;ll find something of interest here. My goal is to provide a unique perspective on data analysis and machine learning by applying these techniques to coffee-related datasets, as well as other datasets in the field of agriculture, biology and genetics.</description></item></channel></rss>